BEAU HODES

CONTACT

BEAUHODES@GMAIL.COM BEAUHODES.COM

PROFILE

I am a computer science student at the University of Kansas with an interest in software development and finding creative business solutions for new technology. I also have experience with full stack development, basic game development, and machine learning. I am a very quick, motivated learner who thrives in a fast-paced environment and enjoys complex problem solving.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

EXPECTED MAY 2021

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS | LAWRENCE, KS GPA: 3.86 MAJOR, 3.81 OVERALL ACT: 33

SKILLS

- Python
- C++/C
- SQL
- TensorFlow
- Linux/Git
- HTML/CSS
- Web Technologies
- JavaScript/Node.js
- Cloud: GCP/Azure
- x/Git Data Structures/Algorithms

PROJECTS

TRENDING WORDS BOT

JANUARY 2021

 Uses JavaScript, Python, and various APIs to monitor keyword-related chatter on Google and Twitter and alert via phone or computer.

PERSONAL SPEECH TRAINER

IN PROGRESS

• Uses a respiratory sensor and Python to help those who stutter, including myself, work on their fluency using computer visuals.

PROGMON

NOVEMBER 2019

 Along with 4 classmates, created a basic fighting game, called Progmon, using Python and Pygame. My responsibilities included game flow design, computer logic, test suite development, and graphic design.

BETLIQUID

IN PROGRESS

 BetLiquid will be an online exchange-based betting platform that allows users to predict the outcome of an event by buying shares in the end result. My responsibilities include data management and API development.

EXPERIENCE

OPERATIONS INTERN

LOCKTON COMPANIES | JUNE 2020 - AUGUST 2020

- Lockton is the world's largest privately held insurance brokerage firm
- Worked on a variety of projects including nuclear verdict research, finding discrepancies in payment systems, and insurance-related case studies

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

PORT TMS | MAY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Port TMS is a cloud-based transportation management software company founded in 2018
- General programmer: Implemented, from back end to front end, a web interface for company developers to save time in the creation and management customer data reports

DATA ANALYTICS CONSULTANT

ASTRA INNOVATIONS | NOVEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- Astra Innovations is a tech company that uses data analytics to help oil and gas wells become more efficient
- Selected relevant data from unconventional oil and gas well data using SQL queries
- Used Google Cloud Platform's AI Prediction Models and Python to find ways to improve drilling performance

WEB DESIGNER

MIDLAND METAL | MAY 2017 - JULY 2017

- Midland metal is a manufacturer, importer, and distributor of fittings, nipples, valves, and accessories founded in 1980
- Communicated directly with clients to develop basic designs for their websites
- Implemented designs and using Wordpress and HTML

KU LEADERSHIP CHALLENGE

JANUARY 2020

 Two day seminar promoting leadership skills and networking sponsored by corporate affiliates

CERTIFICATES

CRYPTOCURRENCY AND BLOCKCHAIN

UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA (ONLINE) | JANUARY 2021

SEQUENCES, TIME SERIES, AND PREDICITON IN TENSORFLOW DEEPLEARNING.AI | AUGUST 2020

BLOOMBERG MARKET CONCEPTS

BLOOMBERG LP | APRIL 2020

IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

COURSERA/IBM | SEPTEMBER 2019

 Nine-course certificate using Python and various algorithms

MICROSOFT: AZURE207X —"DATABASES IN AZURE" EDX | MARCH 2019

SELECTED COURSEWORK

- Software Engineering: Systematic development of software products including life-cycle models, teams, tools, testing, planning, and estimating. Also covered Agile development, and Git version-control.
- Others: Computer Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Computer Security, Calculus I-III, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Databases, Computer Forensics